Good morning. You're watching the
program with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
Thank you for joining us on Thursday,
March 12th. Good morning, John.
>> Morning, Ted. How you doing?
>> I'm good. Trying to hope my voice isn't
too squeaky this uh
uh
inside joke from yesterday. Um so
obviously we're going to be talking
about the uh Iran is uh basically losing
the air war but winning the the sea war.
Uh they have choked the Strait of
Hormuz. We'll be talking about that. Um
and we're we'll talk about the uh the
economic impact with oil back at about
$100 a barrel. And uh you know, we're
going to see I think a ripple effect
throughout the entire global economy
that's uh I think the the Trump
administration would like to sort of
bring in for a soft landing but I'm not
so sure that's likely to happen anytime
soon. John Thune, um a the Republican
leader, is uh sort of at war with his
own con- conference about the Save
America Act. We'll talk about
something that they really shouldn't
want because it will only cost
Republican votes. Democrats should want
it but don't want it even though they'll
get more votes. It's it's insanity but
uh anyway, uh as always, please like,
follow, and share the show. We really
appreciate your support. Uh we're
closing in on 30,000 subscribers. Uh so
um that's on YouTube. Thank you so much
for that. Uh and for your generous
donations and the super chats and all
that. Um as always, uh we will uh try to
get to all of your questions, um
especially the super chats, but all all
of them. Uh so please, if you're
watching live on Rumble or on YouTube,
go ahead in the 9:00 hour and put those
questions into the live chat and
producer Robbie West will get to them.
Speaking of producer Robbie West, let's
bring him in. He has some housekeeping
to take care of as we call it.
>> Howdy. So, I know that there have been
some complaints about missed super chats
at random. I get you. Uh you're paying
money to ask a question. It would only
be polite of us to answer the question
that you paid to have asked. So, if it
does get missed,
we have a we have a workaround.
Take a picture of it, a screenshot. Then
email me. Send me the screenshot of your
question at westglaciergaming at
gmail.com
and I will make sure this is at the top
of the stack.
So, I can't think of a better way to do
this. I'll talk to John and Ted later on
about maybe having one day a week where
we just do Q&A. We'll see what happens.
Can't make that promise, but I will
control whatever I can. So, email me
and I will do everything I can to make
sure that your pithy and witty question
that you paid for is answered in a
timely manner.
>> Yeah, please be advised we definitely if
it If If it's missed, it's an accident.
It's never on purpose.
>> Never.
>> You have You have no idea what it looks
like on the back end. You You have no
idea.
>> [laughter]
>> I can't I can't keep up with it. Yeah,
no. I mean like when Robbie, when you're
out and I'm trying to to keep up with it
John and I are trying to keep up with it
even if we split it up like, "Hey John,
you look at the Rumble. I'll look at the
YouTube." Whatever. It's just like
literally flying by. Um you know, I mean
well look, if you're in the chat, you
sort of know, right? Cuz you see how
fast it moves.
Yeah.
>> Yes. If you get If you get missed, it's
not intentional. It's not us trying to
be jerks. Uh it's just you know, life
happens.
>> We're not ingrates, you know.
Uh yeah, thanks Robbie. I appreciate
that. Um so, the you know, that's uh you
know, it reminds me of uh
uh one one time someone came up to me
No, I read online like, "Oh, Ted Rall's
really mean. I went up to him at an
event at a at Comic-Con and he I he he
didn't talk to me. He didn't pay
attention to me." And I'm like thinking,
"I would never do that, like ever. So,
something must have been up, right? Like
I must have just been talking to someone
else or
you know, I was on the phone or
whatever. I mean, obviously, it had to
be a misunderstanding. And it it kills
me cuz I'm like, you know, I'm a lot of
bad things, but like I'm not that kind
of bad thing.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, so.
Um so, let's let's get into it. We'll be
looking at those questions in just a
second and Robbie will be pumping them
up to put him up for us in the Telegram
chat that we have. Um but in the
meantime,
uh let's talk about the economy. I mean,
I thought it's really interesting.
Uh oil prices are are are soaring.
Uh you know, the we have five or six
vessels who have been that have been
struck now by Iranian fire in the Strait
of Hormuz. Um Trump is saying that the
is urging the captains to have grow some
balls and basically make a
>> their watch their way through.
>> Yeah. Watch their way through.
Um you know, you ever anyone ever see
Captain Phillips? There's only like five
or six dudes on these tankers, right?
>> Yes.
>> And they there's all it's a skeleton
crew. You would think it would be 200
people.
>> They can't defend the ship. They can
protect themselves. There's a way what
they do is they barricade themselves
inside the engine room.
Which is like armored and triple locked
and there's an emergency stash of food
and water in there and they can control
the engine from inside the engine room.
They can override the bridge.
But that's all they can do is disable
the ship and just wait for help to come.
>> Which in a war zone isn't likely to
happen.
>> That's right.
>> And and then like even if they're able
to get in touch by satellite phone, you
know, with you know, corporate in Oslo
or Taipei or whatever, you know, they're
going to say like sit sit tight, you
know, you know, don't move, you know,
you you are not to risk 400 million
dollars of crude oil.
>> And one of the things that I learned Ted
when I was on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee staff because one of
my issues was international piracy and I
brought Captain Phillips down to
testify. We we sat for hours together.
>> That's cool.
>> Um
one of the things that I learned was
that
uh by international treaty
no civilian ship is allowed to carry a
weapon.
>> Mhm.
>> So they're on their own.
>> Yeah, that was wasn't that the
controversy um over the sinking of the
Lusitania?
>> Yeah.
>> That basically the uh cuz obviously it
was carrying material.
>> arms. Yeah.
>> And and like so the Germans the the
Germans said, "Well, this is a fair
target."
>> Mhm.
>> And uh I mean
and that's I guess that's kind of also I
mean the law and doesn't correct me if
I'm wrong doesn't some don't some
aspects of the law of the sea also kind
of deal um you know bleed over into air
transport?
>> Yes, but that's far more controversial
because the US is famously not a
signatory to the law of the sea.
>> Uh the US is always like we don't sign
the mine convention.
>> No.
>> Right? We don't
>> No, we're wrong, wrong, wrong about so
many of these issues.
>> Well, but then John as you know very
well, we signed the convention on
torture against torture.
>> There it is.
>> And you know, but that's just a piece of
paper, you know, it doesn't have the
force of law under as a full treaty
obligation signed and you know, by
ratified by the United States Senate or
anything.
>> Right.
>> So um so the um in the uh IE the IEA
International Energy Agency which is a
consortium of 32 nations
um they just ordered a the release of
400 million barrels of uh oil to be
released from their reserves.
Um the US is is thinking of doing a big
release from its strategic reserve.
But John, my understanding is that this
is a drop in the bucket. It's not going
to really have much of an impact because
the impact of the of the closure of the
Strait of Hormuz is so big that it's
like impossible for any strategic
reserve to make up for that.
>> Yes. And you know, the the funny thing,
too, well, it's not funny.
It's that
Donald Trump, you'll recall,
viciously
um mocked Barack Obama when he released
oil from the strategic oil reserves
saying that it was just a stunt to keep
oil prices down.
Okay, so what are what are you doing?
This is just a stunt keep oil prices
down. It was just 1 week ago, barely 1
week ago, that Donald Trump was bragging
about how
when he took This was so disingenuous.
When he took office,
gas was $6 a gallon in some states. He
meant California, which has nothing to
do with anything. It's that's an unusual
situation.
But now, in many cases, it's a $1.89 a
gallon. Nowhere was it $1.89 a gallon.
Well, now it's it's up a buck a gallon
from a week ago.
>> More.
>> More. I paid I paid 2.569
a week ago.
And yesterday I paid 3.549, so 98 cents
for me.
>> My local station went from 2.55 to 3.85
in 9 days.
So, um you know,
it is it is speaking of piracy, right? I
mean, it's like, come on, the oil you
guys paid for, you know, that oil's been
going through refineries for the last
few years.
>> Exactly.
>> You know, the gas that we're putting
into our cars now, but
they're [__]
>> Exactly right.
>> One time I pulled up to my gas station
in in Long Island, and it was hilarious.
It said was owned by like this very mean
lesbian woman. And and she like just as
I pull up to the curb, she prompts up
and throws this she the the price change
like with a magnet up onto the onto the
pump as I pull up. It was up 20 cents.
I'm like and I go, "Really? She says,
"Now?" And she's like, "I just got the
call."
>> [laughter]
>> Oh my god.
>> So it's like that.
>> So um
but well let's um I got to so John, I
got to ask you a question. By the way,
I'm not sure my tele is your Telegram
loading? I'm not seeing the the live
chats. Are you?
>> Uh I'm not actually.
>> Okay, maybe something's up on Robbie's
side. Well, let me ask
>> what? I wasn't even I just
I was assuming it was just a weirdly
slow day.
>> Robbie, what's going on? Are we not
getting questions?
>> Uh we are. It's glitching. Hold on, I'm
refreshing it.
>> Okay. All right. All right. Cuz we're
not seeing it. All right. I just saw
one. Okay, good. Thanks.
Okay. See, this is the thing. I mean,
with tech stuff, you got to
there's no way we can we can put out the
fires. Um so anyway, uh we got to talk
about the school the you were appalled
we all were when the elementary school
was blown up. Um now we know it was by
the Americans and now we know how it
happened, right? So basically, we talked
a little bit about this this elementary
school. 175 people or more including a
lot of young kids cuz it was an
elementary school and presumably
teachers and staff and maybe parents um
were all blown up um by this Tomahawk uh
missile
um back in the very beginning of the
Iran uh the US and Israeli war against
Iran. Um
the Trump administration denied that the
that the US had anything to do with it,
but now the internal the internal
uh investigation at DOD has confirmed
that like yes, of course it was us. And
uh you know, we
Trump even said like, "Oh, you know,
anyone can have a Tomahawk cruise
missile. Like, you know, Clovis could
have one. Um it's like but that's not
true. Um
so it's targeting data, right? So the
targeting data was basically that this
was this was turned into a school back
somewhere between 2013 and 2016. All
right, so that's 10
to 13 years ago and this is a John
Kiriakou special question, right?
You've you've had dim things to say
about the DIA in the past.
>> Yeah.
>> This appears to be
map information provided by the DIA. So
I have a multiple questions about this
but basically
is it routine for the DIA to suck this
bad? And then my other question is
um are they I mean, okay, it's it's one
thing I understand you have old you have
old information, right? But
if something becomes a target, isn't
there an obligation to
double, triple, quadruple check at this
point just to make sure that
>> Yeah.
>> dot your eyes, cross your T's, make sure
everything's cool.
>> See, this is how we accidentally bombed
the Chinese embassy in Belgrade.
Right? Because the targeting information
is
often wrong,
rarely updated appropriately.
And listen, I know people are going to
complain but I'm going to say it anyway.
DIA
is largely made up of
people who just couldn't make it through
the CIA process.
Like they really, really, really want to
work in Intel. They're not very bright
but
by God, they want to work in Intel and
they end up at DIA.
Yeah, it happens all the time. You know,
this is another thing. You're supposed
to
not just check, double check, triple
check. You're supposed to then send it
to other offices to check, double check,
and triple check to make sure you don't
do things like blow up a girl's school
and kill all the children inside.
So, yeah. It's
>> And also, is it routine for for um the
data to be this [__] old? I mean,
that's really [__] old.
>> Yep.
It is. It's very, very old. Yes. But,
again,
updating it would require them to, you
know, I don't know, look at a satellite
photo and see if there are children
there playing in the yard.
>> Well, that's my question, right? Or put
or send a drone to circle ahead of
beforehand or
>> Yeah.
>> or a satellite or a live satellite feed.
Um John, you know, I know you know this
obviously. Like, you know, the Soviets
used to, you know, they obviously we
knew they had military bases in this
area or whatever, but they would always
sort of move them on the map a few miles
away from really where they really were.
>> Yeah.
>> How does an agency like the Maps agency
or the or the Defense Intelligence
Agency or the CIA,
how do they obtain, let's say, you know,
a map a reliable map of a of an
adversary country that's not voluntarily
providing accurate information? Let's
say you were, you know, China, let's
say.
>> Yeah.
>> What would you you know, how how do they
get how do they know, for example,
this was a Revolutionary Guards
facility until 2013?
>> They have an army of analysts sitting at
these giant light tables like the size
of an architect's draft board drafting
board
>> Mhm.
>> with these
like little telescopes they they look
like little telescope not telescopes,
but like oversized jeweler's loupes.
>> Mhm.
>> And they're looking at
literally every square foot
of a country.
>> And this is spice This is satellite
>> Satellite, yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> So, now with drones it's a lot easier
cuz you can you can have real-time, you
know, feeds. But, um an army of people
just looking foot by foot by foot. And
then once you establish a baseline, it
makes it that much easier. And then one
analyst pass passes it to the next
analyst and then on to the next analyst.
Um it's far easier now with drones
because if you're not sure about
something,
many times you can just send a drone to
go take a closer look at it.
>> So So, is I think this is going to be a
perfect storm, right? It's going to it
turned out to be
five different errors or whatever,
right?
>> Oh, yeah. This should never have
happened, Ted.
>> And um
>> never have happened.
>> Will there be any accountability even
within uh the within the system?
I mean, like in other words, is there,
you know, so no one in
>> No.
>> It's just like sucks to be sucks to be a
a
first-grader in Iran, that's all?
>> When when the president just says, "Eh,
everybody has Tomahawk missiles." when
in fact only the US, the UK, and
Australia, and Japan have them.
And you know, that could have been
anybody. It wasn't us.
Then you know
you know that nobody's going to face any
kind of punishment.
>> It's uh So it So this kind of thing
could and and would keep hap could
happen again.
I mean, what else is there?
>> Just like it happened in the in the
Kosovo War, it happened in the Gulf War.
It happens every time we have an armed
conflict with some other country. And
then we're like, "Oh, our bad. Yeah. Too
bad about that. Sorry." And then we're
supposed to just think that that's going
to be the end of it.
>> And I mean, so
>> terrible.
>> It just seems so um
It just I mean and one of one of the
excuses that's being you know floated on
by sort of corporate media is like well
you know when you're in the early stages
of a war
you know like there's not really enough
time to check everything to check out
all the old targeting data. Right. Okay
but again help me out here. There's no
world in which this wasn't a surprise
for the United States or Israel right? I
mean the United States has been planning
this for months. Right if not longer.
Forever yeah. So
you figure we've been planning this
since 1979 and presumably constantly
updating the targets.
Supposedly. Supposedly. And and
apparently we've taken out 5000 targets
at this stage.
That's That's a lot of That's a lot of
That's to me that's a That's a statistic
that that doesn't mean anything.
Cuz what's a target? A target could be
you know a garage where there are might
or might not be a Jeep inside.
You know? We can call anything we want a
target. Sure.
All right so we'll do some questions.
Yeah. All right we we like the questions
and we're sorry that we missed a few.
Okay Ray thanks $5
John great new RT show deep state
enjoyed it. Thanks for the
I didn't know it was up. Hey thanks I'm
going to check it out. John Smith thanks
for the two hey John I've been
subscribed to the show on YouTube since
2.5k. You should absolutely go to
Hassan's stream. He's not anti-American
he's anti-American imperialism.
I I was just the reason I paused when
you when you spoke just a moment ago.
Greyhorse thanks for the $5 said did you
see Hassan [__] responded to the clip
of you saying that he's not going you're
not going on his stream. He said quite a
lot of choice words about you.
Just wondering what your take on him is.
>> [laughter]
>> You know what his [__] problem is?
We're trying to work something out with
his people. He needs to calm the [__]
down.
And on April the 9th,
we'll get something done.
Holy [__] What's wrong with people?
Relax, buddy.
>> [laughter]
>> Handsome libertarian, question for all
three of us.
What are your thoughts on the report of
Iran onion sleeper cells and Trump
saying he knows about them? Potential
9/11 false flag?
>> Um
No, I I don't think so.
You know, somebody asked me just a week
ago
if there were Iranian sleeper cells in
the United States and I said no.
I still believe the answer is no. I
think that the administration's lying to
us. It's trying to scare us and it's
trying to bring people into line to
support this this war.
There's never been any evidence that
there were Iranian sleeper cells. There
are Iranian
um intelligence officers who often times
are able to get [snorts] into the
country.
Usually not. I shouldn't say often times
that or sometimes able to get into the
country. Usually not. Usually they have
more ease getting into Canada.
But they invariably get caught before
they're even able to do their operation.
So, I'm not worried about the Iranians.
Yeah.
>> All right.
Uh we will. Uh let's take let's move on
here. Um
Jackson McGrath
thanks for the two Australian dollars.
Favorite subject in Islamic
subs
ex a subjects, I guess ex-theology.
Okay. Um
Okay. Jack Samuel 480 3480. Thanks for
the 999. What's going on in NYC? Far
right protester Jack Lang, God, little
neo-Nazi [__] outside mayor's mansion
and counter-protesters clashing then to
top it off ISIS lone wolf, well, wolves,
throwing an IED at the crowd mansion,
what the hell?
I mean
I don't know how they
>> But this isn't really terribly unusual,
right? Right, Ted? They I mean they're
they're always going to be nuts in in
New York or or nuts going to New York to
make some sort of a statement.
>> Yeah. You know, this is a yeah, and this
is look, it's it's not that complicated.
I mean, you know, Eric Adams is a very
controversial mayor, especially on the
far right. He's they've turned him into
a bet noir simply because he's Muslim.
Um, and there it's it's motivated by
racism and you can see it all over like
my ex feed. Everybody I follow is like
all these right-wingers who are like,
oh, is, you know, all Muslims must be
deported and, you know, blah blah blah.
Um, so Laura Loomer and all those kind
of people. So, you know, Jack these are
all like Jack, you know, uh, Jake Lang
is just, you know, trying to, you know,
get notoriety for his cause and then
these two Nimrods, [__] you know,
[__] fools like downloading their
own, you know, join the P,
download your own ISIS flag PDF, you
know, uh, you know,
collect them all,
uh, you know, show up and try to, you
know, make something out of their stupid
wretched excuses for lives.
Yeah, I mean, there's not really a lot
to say about it, unfortunately. I wish
there were. There's no analysis cuz it's
just random stupidity and and and mania
Maxwell Mark, uh, thanks, uh, question
for John and Ted. Strong character in
mainstream media is dead and the gen pop
is desperate for people like you. Could
you two release a follow list of
journalists you consider peers and that
you respect? That's
>> That's a great question.
>> question. I guess I could
I could I'd have to God, it's I hate to
say this, John. It's hard.
I I I'm sure, you know, cuz like I mean
there are some though.
>> The journalists that I have the deepest
respect for, Ted,
are independent journalists.
>> Oh, for sure.
>> People like uh Max Blumenthal, for
example.
>> For sure.
>> I think Max is amazing. Uh Aaron Maté,
absolutely amazing. Kevin Gosztola,
these guys are incredible.
>> Jason Jason Leopold's good.
>> Jason Leopold, absolutely wonderful. And
we might call Jason mainstream. He he's
with Bloomberg.
Jason's fantastic.
But yeah, I mean I'm My mind doesn't
even go to
the mainstream outlets.
Um
>> No.
>> As mainstream as I'm going to get, and
I'm biased cuz I like him and he's a
good guy, is Jake Tapper.
>> Yep. Yeah.
>> I know you go you but go back probably
farther with Jake than I do. Um he he
came to the prison to interview me in
2013, and we've been friends ever since.
>> Yeah, now he he's he's a he's one of the
good ones. I mean, for sure. Uh
yeah. Uh but, you know, the thing is
let's just say he doesn't have full
freedom of movement, right? Like if he
found himself separated from CNN and had
his own show, I guarantee you uh it
would be uh a more
a more Tapperish experience.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. Yeah, I I like him very much.
>> Uh so, uh DG DBG, thanks for the 400. I
don't know if there's a um others or uh
you on or or Jen or whatever. Hey John
and Ted, love you both, but I just
wanted to say I disagree with John's
comments on Jon Stewart being a Zionist.
He's had Medhi, Zoran, uh Oliver, and
Bernie support him. He's called out
Obama and Bibi. I agree he's no lefty.
Yeah, I was
>> Okay, I I stand corrected.
>> I don't I mean, yeah, I don't know.
>> He's always Yeah, I'll tell you what I
met him one time.
I met him one time, and and he left the
the the visit
I mean, was in his office, and the visit
just left a sour taste in my mouth
because
he had these Emmys just kind of strewn
on the couch where you couldn't sit on
the couch cuz there were Emmys just
randomly laying across them.
And and I commented when I when I went
out, I said, "Oh my god, he has so many
Emmys that he just throws them on the
couch like that?"
And the intern said, "No.
He loves those Emmys. He does that to
make it look like ah, it's no big deal.
I just win these Emmys, and I don't even
care. I just throw them on my couch."
And I was like, "Oh, he's one of these
guys, a poser."
>> Yeah, [laughter] yeah. I hope I'm not
offending anyone, but I kind of feel
like that's people like who who like
frame their college degree in their own
house or something like that.
>> Yeah, I never understood that either. I
don't even know where my degrees are.
>> I'm not sure I could put my I know I
have them in a box somewhere.
>> Yeah, they must be in a box in the
garage, but I genuinely don't know where
my degrees are.
>> Yeah, it's just sort of like No, I kind
of get like why a doctor or a
psychologist would have it cuz, you
know, you want to make sure they went to
medical school and whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> But, you know, although I don't even
know I don't really need that either.
I'm going to assume they went to medical
school, right?
>> Ryan Grim, Katie Halper both are
awesome. I'm supposed to see Ryan
tomorrow.
Yeah, they're they're terrific. There
are a lot of great independent
journalists out there.
>> Uh there are. There are. Um Miss Moth,
uh thanks for the 10 bucks. Greetings
from Tbilisi, Georgia. Have either of
you been to Georgia? And what do you
think the of the Caucasus countries
should do given their location between
Russia and Iran? Appreciate you guys a
lot. I have been to Tbilisi. How about
you?
>> I've not, but I am proud to say that my
23andMe test shows that I am something
like 12% uh from the Caucasus. I've And
and another thing, too. I don't know
why, but but my
Tik Tok algorithm constantly feel
feeds me
these videos of people doing traditional
Georgian singing that I am absolutely
addicted to. Huh.
>> [laughter]
>> It's just fantastic. And I cut out a a
recipe from the New York Times the other
day for this traditional Georgian lamb
stew that I'm going to make this
weekend.
>> Oh, well, that's what I was about to
say. Like
my main takeaway from Tbilisi is you're
in danger of getting fat cuz the food is
very good.
>> I can't wait to go. I've got to
>> And I love the wine, too. Um
>> The wine is you know, I've subscribed to
Wine Spectator magazine for 20 plus
years. Georgian wine is is some of the
best in the world and it's the most
overlooked.
>> So true. Nobody ever And it's very
affordable. Um see So yeah, so in terms
of what they should do,
look, they could become a transit point
in a true
you know, Russian-Iranian military
alliance that goes beyond just an
intelligence cooperation agreement. It
could be those could become a conduit
point.
But you know, traditionally countries
that are in places like that between
great powers
>> Yeah.
>> always survive by playing off both sides
and trying to maintain as much you know,
base level neutrality as possible.
So I think that's probably and that's
obviously what they're doing.
But they're I think I mean, I would say
Georgia is definitely more
um traditionally it was more in Russia's
sphere of influence for sure.
>> Agreed.
>> Uh
Grayhorse88, thanks for the five.
Okay, so you you already addressed that.
But thanks for the five bucks anyway.
Gospel of Tommy, thanks for the $4.99.
Love the show, guys. All evidence points
to them bombing those girls on purpose.
Why did they do it? I you know, look, I
hate I hate the the people who are who
started this war.
I don't think they did this on purpose.
I think they thought it was they they
thought they were lazy. They they were
reckless. They didn't care enough about
the innocent lives to just say like to
double triple quadruple check it out. I
think but I don't think they said, "Oh
look, there be
uh you know, an elementary school and
let's blow it up." Cuz it's going to
cause trouble.
Um and it's going to then have people
like us and the New York Times and you
know, Democratic senators up their ass.
So I don't I really don't believe they
did it on purpose.
>> I I I don't think they did it on
purpose.
>> I think they're just [__] dumbasses.
Now that doesn't make it any different.
I mean, like look, if you're DUI and you
and you kill someone because you were
[__] too stupid to call a taxi and
you got into a car drunk, well you
probably didn't kill anyone on purpose,
did you? But they're still just as
[__] dead cuz of your recklessness.
So to me it's like a difference it's a
distinction without a difference.
>> You know, I I I was watching one of
these reality shows, one of these court
shows yesterday. And um
Oh, I'm seeing that that it looks like
we may have just bombed children's
hospital in Tehran.
Lovely. Check that out, too. Um so I'm
watching this cop show yesterday and
it's this guy
this this defendant
>> [clears throat]
>> he's arrested three times for possession
with intent to distribute PCP, which I
didn't even know people still did PCP.
>> It's so it's it's so 80s.
>> It's so 80s. Angel dust. So the judge
reluctantly gives him bond. Said, "You
better clean up your act. I'm going to
give you bond. It's your last chance."
He he goes out on bond,
smokes PCP and hits and kills a guy.
So
he's like, "Your honor,
I really like to have a second chance."
And the judge is like, "This was your
fourth chance.
And you killed somebody." He He up
getting 50 years.
But you know
>> 50 years is insane, but that's our
system.
>> 50 years is insane, but it was it was
his
fourth
PCP related uh conviction.
>> I'd be okay with
>> I hadn't even heard the term
>> Just duct tape the guy to a board and
never let him leave anywhere.
>> Yeah, that's pretty much what it's going
to come down to.
>> God. Uh
Uh John Nippleton, Josh Nippleton, my
apologies. Thanks for the $13.99
Canadian.
Uh hey Telly and John, love how kind and
thoughtful you both are. Question for
John, during your time in the Muslim
world, did you ever have to read and
analyze the Quran in order to understand
Muslim ideology?
>> No, but I certainly studied it and and
read read it in its entirety when I was
in college. Um you know
in in the State Department, less less so
in the CIA, but in the State Department
um
it's all about
it's all
about data tuning.
Um the only time I ever really needed
to have even
any background in the Quran was when
um Ambassador David
Ransom, for whom I worked in Bahrain,
went to meet the Minister of Awqaf and
Islamic Affairs. And I was the
translator.
Uh and the note taker.
That was the only time the Quran ever
came up.
>> I mean the Yeah, the implication that
we've heard post-9/11 is that Colonel
like, you know, everybody's following,
you know, that that [clears throat] that
the that there's a
a really tight obvious link between the
religion and the and the politics and
particularly Islamic terrorism. And I
think
I mean
John, this is your area of expertise. I
mean, but my impression for example in
Afghanistan was that oh so much of this
is cultural and tribal as well. A lot
more of it and and that often the Quran
is sort of bent and and interpreted to
fit whatever the you know, the cultural
interpretation is.
>> That is absolutely true.
>> and stuff like that.
>> Absolutely true. And that's why in Islam
just as in Christianity, just as in
Judaism,
there are so many different
bents to it, you know?
>> Yeah, I mean it's it's billions of
people.
>> Yeah.
2 billion Muslims, 2 and 1/2 billion
Christians, and there are 99 ways from
Sunday, no pun intended, to interpret
the tenets of it.
>> It's like the Simpsons line, right? Like
whether you're Christian, Muslim, or and
then they have there's Apu,
miscellaneous.
>> [laughter]
>> Thank you, come again.
>> Um
Vilmar Air, thanks for the two Canadian
dollars. Scared there's no off-ramp now.
What next for DXB?
>> I'm scared there's no off-ramp as as
well.
I think this is a serious problem.
>> I don't think there's an off-ramp right
now.
>> Mhm.
>> Um I mean yeah, I mean the thing is
okay, so I mean look, the Iranians don't
want their their lawn mowed, right? As
the Israelis say it. They don't want
this to happen anymore. They need some
kind of
permanent deal. Otherwise, there's no
reason for them not to keep fighting.
>> Yeah.
Um we have an ad we don't want to lose.
>> Okay, let's do it. Sorry, thank you for
that, John.
Um okay, still haven't tried 1775
coffee.
Now is your deal Now is your Now is your
shot. The 1775 starter kit just dropped,
only 1,000 units. You're getting the
bold dark roast that hits hard, the
smooth, medium roast in the vitality
mushroom coffee for clean energy and low
laser focus, no crash, all single
origin, small batch, toxin-free, and
mold-free. Plus, you're also getting a
gold spoon clip because freedom isn't
scooped with plastic, a frother strong
enough to stir up your coffee and your
mother-in-law's opinions, and a black
1775 tumbler. $170 worth of coffee and
gear, yours for 99. This is for the ones
who've been watching 1775 blow up on
Rumble wondering if it's actually worth
it. Spoiler, it is. Go to
1775coffee.com/studio
and grab your starter kit before they're
gone. Bold beans, clean fuel, and a
morning routine that stands for
something just like Rumble does. Okay,
thank you for that, John. I would have
easily just blown through that, but now
I have to go back and find out where I
was. Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, here we go. KJ164, $9.99, thank
you so much. Hi Ted, hi John. Since
Turkey pulled 92 billion in economic
assets from Israel, do you think they're
getting ready to attack? You deserve all
the success you're getting, John.
>> Oh, thank you. Do you know the words do
we think the Turks are ready to attack?
>> I I think they're not going to attack
the Israelis.
>> I will let you in on a little secret.
Last night I had dinner with two senior
officials from the Turkish Foreign
Ministry.
And
we talked about this very issue. And as
soon as I brought it up, they both they
looked at each other and they both
started smiling.
And they said,
"This is not going to happen. There is
not going to be hostilities between
Turkey and Israel, but
if the Israelis were to provoke, and I
thought this was so interesting, Ted, I
I had not thought of it.
If the Israelis were to attack Turkey,
Turkey would destroy them.
And Turkey would not ask NATO to um
invoke Article 5.
>> Would Israel uh pull the Samson option,
though?
>> We talked about that.
>> Yeah.
>> And he said um
he didn't think so because Turkey has no
interest whatsoever in occupying Israel.
>> Mhm.
>> It would be just to bloody Israel's, you
know, face and nose
and tell them you stay on your side of
the border and we'll stay on ours.
>> Yeah, [__] off and go away.
>> That's right.
>> But I don't think the Israelis are
stupid enough to do that.
>> I can't imagine. The Israelis do a lot
of stupid things, but not something that
stupid.
>> Overthrowing Assad, that was stupid.
>> Yeah, but you attack a NATO country just
cuz you don't like their leader?
>> Nah.
>> Nah, that's not going to happen. Um
uh the uh new uh the new uh Ayatollah
Mojtaba uh Khamenei
um has just issued, this is breaking
news,
statement um about so dear combatant
brothers, the demand of the masses in
the continuation of an effective and
regret-inducing defense he did not
appear on camera. He said the lever of
closing the Strait of Hormuz must
certainly continue to be used as well.
Studies have been conducted on opening
other fronts in which the enemy has
little experience and would be highly
vulnerable. I'm I'm reading Cyber here.
Um their activation will take place if
the wartime situation continues and in
accordance with the considerations of
expediency. Um okay, and then there's
just sort of some boilerplate thanks to
the to their troops. Um John, when I was
when I was last in in uh entering Iran,
I was questioned by Iranian intelligence
officers for about 4 hours at the border
>> Wow, 4 hours?
>> with Afghanistan, yeah. And toward the
end of the conversation, and by the way,
these guys are like they're like exactly
like Mossad guys. They kind of like
could be twins, you know? They're always
like in their 20s, they kind of like
have big shit-eating grins, and they
always wear like a sports jacket and a
and a and a and just a t-shirt
underneath.
Um
They're like the same. And the except
the Iranian ones are nicer. And the And
anyway, at the end of it, the guy says
he's like, "Can I get your email
address? I just really want to keep in
touch with you." And I'm like, "You
don't really want to just keep in touch
with me, do you?" And he started
laughing. And I was like And this was in
When was this? 2011. And it's like he's
like not looking to keep in touch. I
think he wanted to like we're going to
get your email address and we'll hack
it, right? And
>> [clears throat]
>> And that was a long time ago. I mean,
how are Do we know how Iran's
cyber warfare
uh what their cyber warfare capabilities
are?
>> You know, all we see in the reporting is
when Iran is the victim of cyber
warfare.
I I don't think I know anything about
Iran's capabilities.
>> That's interesting.
>> we we hear about Stuxnet and how the the
Americans and the Israelis were crowing
about their their success with Stuxnet.
>> Well, Iran's The Iranians were retards.
They were. Yeah.
>> Yeah, they were.
And then Stuxnet, you know, leaked and
went all over the Middle East.
>> Yes.
Yeah, it's crazy.
Um So, yeah, no, I I don't think there's
an off-ramp.
You know, um
>> I don't either.
>> Uh
Ted and John, thanks for the 10 bucks
from uh Is Is Is Zelu. Could you talk
about the CIA's surveillance targeting
program,
uh EM weapons, uh electromagnetic I
assume, mind control, and gangstalking
on innocent civilians? People say it's a
torture program.
Targeted Justice is fighting and then to
and then I don't know, it's cut off. But
anyway, that you get you get the gist of
it.
>> Yeah, the CIA doesn't do that.
The CIA hasn't even experimented with it
since 1975.
Um it's my understanding that there is
no such thing as gangstalking.
>> What is gangstalking?
>> Gangstalking but I get I I get these
these queries almost every day. I got
one yesterday.
Um where people say, well I I'll tell
exactly what the guy said yesterday.
He said that he's been under close-in
surveillance
for the last 6 years. He's an Uber
driver and the CIA has been following
him everywhere he goes. Just yesterday
he was in the grocery store and he
turned to look and there was a man
staring at him. And then when he's
laying in bed at night, they're using
electromagnetic weapons against him and
it gives him a headache and he can't
sleep and they follow him everywhere he
goes. It's like, no.
That's mental illness.
>> Mhm.
>> You need to see a psychiatrist, not a
former CIA officer.
>> But what does gangstalking mean?
>> Gangstalking is when it's a whole gang
of people
and they're constantly on you. Like some
are following you close in, some are
following you from a distance, some are
beaming waves at you, some are in cars
around you. It's all made up. It's all
in their minds.
>> Yeah, I mean that wouldn't I mean you
tell me but aren't intel intelligence
operations are expensive, salaries are
expensive.
Uh if you were you know and you don't
want to attract attention, right?
>> You know, an operation like that
at most would last a day or two and it
would be targeted against somebody who
had very specific information that the
CIA needed.
Not some Uber driver driving around, you
know, Kentucky.
>> [laughter]
>> It's just not real life. And this this
targetedjustice.targetjustice.com
or .org um
it's a place where all these people go
to to
talk about how the CIA is, you know,
stealing their dreams and
planted a chip in their in the filling
in their tooth and
communicating through some kind of
waves.
>> I have heard like a funny I mean I I
have heard I forget where I read this,
but apparently it is some people have
credibly picked up
>> Yes.
>> like AM/FM radio waves through their
fillings and then they thought that it
meant that they were being spied on.
>> Yes.
>> But really they were just picking up
radio waves.
>> Absolutely true.
>> Or like, you know, or from cop cars or,
you know, whatever whoever's using, you
know, construction workers using radio.
Um
Okay, let's see. Um
Thanks for the dollar from Hey Mike.
John, you should go on
I'm going to tell you to go on things.
Slavos
Halkias
Slavi World Podcast, my two favorite
Greek Americans.
>> I never heard of it, but I'm going to
check it out.
>> Okay. Uh
>> Thanks.
>> BJ O'Donnell, five bucks. Thank you very
much. Hey all, with the information that
AI is playing a part in the selection of
targets for the current war in Iran, is
it possible the school was targeted by
AI? What would be the implication of
this? Now, the thing is that question
has been directly answered by the
administration. They deny it stridently.
Um I'm in
I'm inclined to believe them here.
>> I I think this was a human error.
>> Yeah.
>> In fact, the Washington Post on the
front page of the Washington Post this
morning, they had a a very long
explanation of how like this was [__]
up every step of the way.
>> Oh, I look forward to reading that. It
pisses me off though. I mean it I mean
it look, as far as I'm concerned, I just
want to be clear. Morally, to me,
recklessness to that extent is no
different than if it was intentional.
Um the the moral culpability of the
United States and President Trump and
everyone in his administration who has
anything to do with this is the same. To
me, it's a war crime either way. Like,
who cares? Like, oh, I just didn't give
a [__] I didn't I didn't do I didn't I
didn't you know, to do my I didn't give
enough I didn't do my homework, and so
I'm sorry your daughter's dead.
That doesn't really help me as a dad,
does it?
>> No.
No.
Um
Uh MM5478, thanks for the 10. Just a few
dollars to say thanks for my career
public defender. You guys are fighting
for our democracy and the world of law.
>> Well done, gentlemen.
>> Oh, the public defenders are the unsung
heroes of the American judicial system.
They're grotesquely overworked and
underpaid, and we need lots more and
lots more money to give to them.
>> Here, here. Couldn't agree more. Jackson
McGrath, uh exclude thanks for the two
Australian dollars. Excluding Islamic
theology, uh I I don't know what that
is.
I think it's a follow-up to a previous
comment. Um Repentance 1645, thanks for
the 4.99 British pounds. Uh with all
these events unfolding, nobody seems to
be speaking about Hamas.
>> Right.
>> bringing this up. Do you both believe
they may strike again or be planning
something?
I
Well, I mean, anything's possible. Look,
they Talk about resilience, right? I
mean, those guys are They're like
cockroaches. You can't kill them. Um
They're I mean, I think I think
survival's the win.
I don't know, John. What do you think? I
mean, Hezbollah has opened up a
front against Israel for real, you know,
3 years late, but I guess. But, uh
but here we are.
Could Hamas have some trick up their
sleeve? It's hard to believe at this
stage.
>> It would be hard to believe because
because their their patrons have
have kind of been taken out, at least
temporarily. Sure, I think we should
expect Hamas to reconstitute itself. It
will never be a real threat to Israel,
and it will result in, um,
in Israeli counterstrikes and
counterattacks that would dwarf anything
that Hamas could do to the Israelis.
So, kind of more of the same, I think.
>> Oh, oh, yeah. I I I think that's good.
But, I think look, I think that's a
valuable
a a you know, reminder that we should
keep a we should definitely keep an eye
on, uh, on Hamas. Um, add, uh, add the
ballad. Uh, thanks for the 1,000
Nigerian whatever the currency of
Nigeria is. Thank you. Greetings from
Lago Lagos. I've never heard John talk
about Nigeria. Uh, interested to know if
he's ever had anything with to do with
Nigeria during his career.
>> Not a single thing. I will say that my
colleagues in the Counterterrorism
Center
thoroughly enjoyed working with the
Nigerians. We have a close relationship
with the Nigerians, especially,
uh, in the fight against, uh, terrorism
in the Sahel.
So, relations are good.
Close cooperation.
But, I I never had occasion to go. You
know, even when I was doing training,
counterterrorist training, um,
there weren't many of us in that branch.
It was a branch of like four guys
and a chief. And, um,
I was all Middle East and then I think I
toward the end I picked up Thailand.
But, yeah, Africa wasn't my wasn't my
thing.
>> Um, speaking of the Sahel, uh, culture
junkie, uh, thanks for the five euros. I
want to hear more about the Sahel region
and the roles of countries like Algeria
in there.
>> Yeah, the Sahel is a is a godforsaken
mess.
Um,
they they are the definition of poor,
desperate,
um,
there's no oil,
right? So, it's not like an oil boom's
going to happen.
>> as we know.
>> That's as far as we know.
Um
>> I've started saying that because the
places that we thought never had oil
>> Guyana
>> Kyrgyzstan
>> Kyrgyzstan, that's right.
>> Sorry, sorry, not to not Kyrgyzstan,
Tajikistan.
>> Oh, was it Tajikistan? Geez, they're
even more poor than Kyrgyzstan.
>> Yeah, so they're going to be very happy
about it. Yeah, so apparently there's
like new deep drilling technology and uh
they can go down 1.5 miles uh and
>> You know the Russians developed that.
>> And they found it well, maybe the
Russians passed it on to the Tajiks cuz
they have very close relations.
>> Interesting. The Russians got down so
far. They went down like 3 miles
and they had to stop because the drill
bits kept melting.
>> Oh, from the
the heat from the earth
>> Yeah, uh-huh.
>> Oh, that's cool.
>> Yeah.
>> That's great. You know, another thing I
read is that oil workers at oil
derricks, because it's um you know, it's
rotted mostly rotting plants, but they
pull out like
they pull out like uh you know, 200
million-year-old, you know, ferns and
stuff and then they fall apart when they
hit the air.
>> Wow.
>> So cool. Uh you think it's dead
dinosaurs, but it's really not. Uh
Uh John, this is a question from
Christine of $799 Australian dollars.
How do you rate agents from other
intelligence agencies? Are there any
respect, hate, fear, etc.? Have you had
much exposure to them in the field?
Well, obviously
>> Oh, pooh.
Lots and lots of exposure. You know, I
said I said to somebody the other day,
you know the scene in every James Bond
movie where James bumps into the CIA
guy.
>> Yeah.
>> that's in all the movies is because that
happens every single day.
And you're like, "Hello, John.
Hello, Nigel.
>> [laughter]
>> Stay away from the Deputy Prime
Minister, Nigel.
>> He's mine.
>> [laughter]
>> That happened to me once in Kuwait. We
were both going after the same target. I
see this guy is like, [__] He comes up
to me, he's like, hello John. I said,
hello Ian.
>> [laughter]
>> What are you doing here?
I had to deal with this one French guy
one time. So, I was instructed to meet
with a French intelligence officer.
So, I called him and I said, hey, how
are you? I'm John. Nice to talk to you.
Would you like to get together for
lunch? And he's like, uh yes, meet me at
the intersection of uh
First Avenue and Maple Street, right?
I'm like, okay, that's odd.
>> Why not just give me the name of a
restaurant?
>> Yeah. So, I'm standing there on the
corner, and then he comes down the side
street, makes a quick right turn, and
he's like, jump in.
And I said,
you set me up for a car pickup meeting?
It's called a CPU. A car pickup meeting?
I I am not your asset. We're colleagues.
I said, I'm walking down to this
restaurant down here. I'll meet you
there, but I'm not getting in your car.
I'm offended.
>> What do you I mean, what I mean, why are
you offended? What was
>> A car pickup is you've done a
surveillance detection route to get to
an intersection, an intersection on a
black road. Black meaning not a main
road, so nobody can see you.
Right? So,
>> [clears throat]
>> you're going down this road, you make a
quick right, the agent jumps in your
car, and ducks down, and you continue
on. So, even if you are being followed,
nobody saw the agent get in your car.
Well, buddy, we're having lunch
to discuss some joint operation. I'm not
getting in your car. Yeah, I'm not your
recruited asset.
French.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, I mean, that's my family. Um
Turek thanks for the five bucks. Uh
seems to hope the war will cancel or win
the midterms. Do you think he's right? I
agree with that analysis. I don't think
it can possibly win the midterms. I
mean, look, here's the thing. You have a
war that at most is approved of or
tolerated by 27% of the public, 40% by
some accounts, right? I mean, wars never
gain in popularity, ever. World War II
didn't gain in in in in popularity, and
it was the most popular American war
ever. I mean, wars are hard, wars kill
people, wars cost money. Uh you know,
the public turns against them. There's
no world in which, you know, we look
back in December and say, "Wow, you
know, the Republicans picked up seats in
the house, and it turned out it's
because of the war." That's not
possible. So, I think it's a it could be
part of an excuse to declare an a
national emergency and cancel
an election, you know,
or to try to do that, I think. I know it
sounds paranoid. That's But, I mean, if
All I keep I keep coming back to it. I
mean, I think if I'm Donald Trump, I
don't want to go to jail in 2029.
That means I got to cancel 2028. And And
it's easier to cancel 2026 than it is to
cancel 2028. And if you cancel 2026,
then it's easier, like Zelenskyy, to go
back later and say, "Oh, you know, well,
we canceled the parliamentary elections.
Now we'll cancel I mean, that's my
thinking.
>> I pray to God that you're wrong.
>> Me, too.
Me, too. But,
I don't know. We have consistently been
taken by surprise with some of these
issues. So, I'm not making any
predictions.
>> All right, we've got a bunch of super
chats to get through, and I do want to
get to them and and to any others that
we can. Um but, I do want to ask you
about the Save America Act. So, you
know, we talked about this like my
column last week, not the current one.
Um you know, basically, you and I both
talked about how we both agree
that the Save America Act basically
disproportionately disenfranchises
uh you know people who don't can't put
their hands on a passport or a or a
birth certificate with the same name
that they currently have like they got
married you know most likely that or
they got or let's say they transit they
transitioned but that's a fraction of 1%
so
Republicans are fighting for it even
though it's going to hurt them at the
polls Democrats are against it even
though it's going to help them at the
polls
now President Trump though it's a full
court press on the right is leaning on
John Thune and you know basically he's
demanding
a you know
what's his name
Jimmy Stewart
Mr Smith goes to Washington goes to
Washington he wants a talking filibuster
old school you know maybe you know where
your diapers and
>> that is old school and it's a lot of
work
>> and apparently and and Thune is like
says well we don't even have the votes
to do the talking filibuster in other
words we just don't have as as Donald
Trump would say you don't have the cards
like
so what's going on here on the
Republican side like
>> well John Thune is
is exhibiting something called what's
the name of it leadership
>> oh right that
>> right that something I had to think
about because we haven't seen it
anywhere in Washington for so long
>> right
>> John Thune is is taking the long view
here
that if you want to maintain your power
and authority not just yours personally
but the bodies power and authority
then you're going to maintain the
filibuster of course Donald Trump wants
to do away with the filibuster every
president wants to do away with the
filibuster so he can ram his his
projects through
but
Thune knows that
and this is a lesson that Harry Reid
learned the hard way
if you do away with the filibuster,
the other side's going to
be back in power, probably sooner rather
than later, and you're going to be
screwed.
You know, Obama wanted so badly to force
through his judicial nominees. And so,
Harry Reid lifted the filibuster
when it came to judicial nominees, and
that's how we have all these right-wing
crazy people on the Supreme Court. That
was Harry Reid's fault.
And John Thune doesn't want to make it
worse.
>> John, um I'm I'm very like mortified. We
have like six more or seven more uh
super chats to get to uh in just a
couple of minutes. Um the QP sub, uh
thanks for the $50. Mr. Kuriakou, we
respect what you did and wish you
success with your pardon. How important
is Romania for US military positioning
toward the Middle East today? Also, is
there credible evidence of CIA
involvement in Romania's 1989
revolution? I guess that's against uh
Nicolae Ceaușescu.
>> Ceaușescu. Um oh man, I wish I had 5
minutes for this. Uh
Romania is increasingly important uh
vis-à-vis the Middle East. The Greeks
can't take any more American, you know,
planes, ships,
all that stuff. It's full. Everything's
full. The Turks are doing their own
thing. The next best bet is uh Romania,
maybe Bulgaria, but Romania and the
United States are very close. The
military's, the intelligence services
are very close. So, Romania is playing
that role.
>> SPRSlaav, thanks for the tenner. Uh a
military that can drop a bomb through a
window does not accidentally hit a
school. We've been witnessing the use of
the Dahiya doctrine in Palestine and now
Iran. It is simply terrorism. I mean,
look, we don't know,
of course, we it's and you know, but I
there's a big, you know, let's not
conflate accuracy with by GPS with uh
you know, you could we could definitely
hit the we can hit the target. The
question is, do we know what the target
is?
>> That's the thing. Robbie says he needs
to pop on real quick. Okay, here we go.
>> Howdy, howdy, real quick. I know we're
almost out of time and there's a bunch
of rants and super chats. I need y'all
to do me a favor. Take a picture of it.
Take a picture of your rant, email it to
me, westglaciergaming@gmail.com.
I will put it on the top of the stack
tomorrow morning.
>> Thank you, Robbie. You just made me this
happen.
>> Okay, and
then like also thank you for addressing
gangstalking. That's Hog's Canine 2
Buck. Love the show from Tristan. Thanks
for the 1999.
Surprised Judeo-Christian tagline sticks
when Islam and Muslims love and revere
Jesus and Mother Mary. Propaganda
against Islam and Muslims keeps natural
relations from further forming.
>> That's that's that's true. Yes.
>> Yeah, that is true.
Fellas, okay, we're going to these two
they're going to have to go with the two
bottom ones, Robbie. We're going to do
them tomorrow. Thank you so much. Our
apologies for the not being able to get
to everything, but that's how it goes.
We are here 9:00 a.m. Eastern Time
Monday through Friday. We'll be back
tomorrow, Friday, March 13th.
And hopefully have a happy Friday the
13th. John, nice to see you as always.
>> Thanks, everybody.
>> Stay tuned for the TMI show coming up
right now. DMZ America podcast with
Vietnam vet and legendary editorial
cartoonist
Jeff Danziger [clears throat] will be
joining Scott D'Antuono and I at 11:00
a.m. Eastern Time. We're weekly only on
Thursdays. Thanks, everyone. Bye.
Bye.
>> [music]
>> Mhm.